[{"id": "6015f858fe83fe1f2a824c2c", "question": "Under whose presidency were the waters in the fountains of the White House first dyed green in honor of Saint Patrick's Day?", "answer": "Barack Obama", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a74d", "question": "Which US state is home to the Catskill Mountains?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb31", "question": "What magazine began publishing its annual list of the 500 most-successful companies in the US in 1955?", "answer": "Fortune", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ce8", "question": "What singer-songwriter played bass in the New Wave band \"'Til Tuesday\"?", "answer": "Aimee Mann", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe12f17e39efa6330e0fed6", "question": "Where is Great Sand Dunes National Park?", "answer": "Colorado", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339233", "question": "What band took on Will Champion as its drummer even though he didn't play drums at the time?", "answer": "Coldplay", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd664cfa5bfecdd737e0858", "question": "What animal does cashmere come from?", "answer": "Goat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b591", "question": "What does the abbreviation MBA stand for in the MBA master's degree designation?", "answer": "Master of Business Administration", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0b1", "question": "What did the band The Clash rock?", "answer": "The Casbah", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d51", "question": "Author Margaret Atwood is a graduate of which Canadian University?", "answer": "University of Toronto", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5971dd5089261e916c8e099d", "question": "At what wind speed does a tropical storm become a hurricane?", "answer": "74mph (119km/hr)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e82", "question": "During what war was the novel \"The Hornet's Nest\" set?", "answer": "American Revolution", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefc1176ce05a3942286f0e", "question": "In the Bourne film series, what is Jason Bourne's real name?", "answer": "David Webb", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b196", "question": "What is the birth name of US President Bill Clinton?", "answer": "William Jefferson Blythe III", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7e0", "question": "Which US state is home to both the highest and lowest points in the contiguous 48 US states?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59008bc9cf842fa4c4ba969a", "question": "In which Verdi opera does Violetta sing \"Sempre libera\"?", "answer": "La Traviata", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8f9df01dd7bf43be5e84f", "question": "As of 2020, what is the name of the largest submarine in the world?", "answer": "Dmitriy Donskoy, TK-208", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe734eaeec85e375820b23f", "question": "Who served as Hitler's Deputy Fuhrer from 1933 to 1941?", "answer": "Rudolph Hess", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af94", "question": "Who popularized the Christmas tree in England in the 19th century?", "answer": "Prince Albert", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af49", "question": "Where was Albert Einstein born?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58c8a86b90aac110e416708e", "question": "What is the name of the weak alcoholic cider that is made from the solid remains of the pressed apples??", "answer": "Ciderkin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c29a", "question": "What planet has the shortest year?", "answer": "Mercury", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1f8", "question": "What year did Volkswagen introduce the Golf R32 model?", "answer": "2002", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b447", "question": "What year did Joseph Merrick die?", "answer": "1890", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4f9", "question": "What do you call a fat that is liquid at room temperature?", "answer": "Oil", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6562bae7e414034b5aec2", "question": "Which ancient civilization created zodiac signs?", "answer": "Babylonia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133985c", "question": "In the movie \"Howl's Moving Castle\", Calcifer was voiced by which actor?", "answer": "Billy Crystal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c873", "question": "A tetragon is geometric shape that has how many sides?", "answer": "Four", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398ae", "question": "What movie followed the adventures of Marty McFly?", "answer": "Back to the Future", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec8557ec223966ae8f8804", "question": "Which famous golf player was nicknamed \"Golden Bear\"?", "answer": "Jack Nicklaus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5e7", "question": "What color is an adult Bald Eagle's beak?", "answer": "Yellow", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b526", "question": "In what orientation should one not store a typical beer?", "answer": "On their side", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa31", "question": "What is the capital of Luxembourg?", "answer": "Luxembourg City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338972", "question": "Where does Harry Potter have a lightning-shaped scar?", "answer": "On his forehead", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9af", "question": "What mountain is the tallest point in Ecuador?", "answer": "Chimborazo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aece", "question": "What was the second successful mass produced car by the Ford Motor Company called?", "answer": "Model A", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58f169fbf7c52aae91cc07d6", "question": "What US state is the Sturgis Pretzel House located in?", "answer": "Pennsylvania", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c91", "question": "What John Steinbeck novel is based on the biblical story of Cain & Abel?", "answer": "East of Eden", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5aab2f9058d116dab4aecb4b", "question": "What's the name of the technique for collecting measurements at a distance?", "answer": "Telemetry", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe76ba9eec85e375820b2c6", "question": "Which ski resort is known as the \"The Queen of the Dolomites\"?", "answer": "Cortina, Italy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad17", "question": "Which of Henry VIII's wives was the only one to bear him a legitimate, surviving son?", "answer": "Jane Seymour", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338979", "question": "What card game is featured in the novel \"Casino Royale\"?", "answer": "Baccarat", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389f8", "question": "What song about her age did Charmain Carr sing in the movie version of \"The Sound of Music\"?", "answer": "Sixteen Going on Seventeen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b67e", "question": "How many points must the victor score in a game of cribbage?", "answer": "61 or 121", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ff8", "question": "Who plays the title character in the 1955 musical \"Daddy Long Legs\"?", "answer": "Fred Astaire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7c9", "question": "Who won a Nobel Prize for discovering nuclear fission?", "answer": "Otto Hahn", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60062a43c9d816e292245c16", "question": "What American artist is known for paintings of flags?", "answer": "Jasper Johns is an American painter, sculptor and printmaker associated with Abstract expressionism, Neo-Dada, and Pop art.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600cc6536de0eb824d4052f7", "question": "What is the official state fruit of New Hampshire?", "answer": "Pumpkin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f02", "question": "What author created the character of Perry Mason?", "answer": "Erle Stanley Gardner", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc84", "question": "The 2007 rule banning suspended NFL players from signing with the CFL was named for what player?", "answer": "Ricky Williams", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dc8", "question": "Whose sidekick was named Passepartout?", "answer": "Phileas Fogg", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fed2bbaec223966ae8f8911", "question": "What is the name of the smelly green ghost in \"Ghostbusters\"?", "answer": "Slimer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be77", "question": "What does an NFL referee signal by stretching his arms out at his sides with his palms down?", "answer": "Unsportsmanlike Conduct", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339385", "question": "In which US state does \"The Blair Witch Project\" take place in?", "answer": "Maryland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bbd535000d154d7af00b8dc", "question": "Which band recorded and released the song\"Cotton Eye Joe\"?", "answer": "Rednex", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394a0", "question": "In what state was the TV show \"B.J. and Bear\" set?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5ed", "question": "What are the four largest islands in Canada?", "answer": "Baffin, Victoria, Ellesmere and Newfoundland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fede5326ce05a3942286de8", "question": "Who stars as Hannah Brown in the movie version of Irving Berlin's \"Easter Parade\"", "answer": "Judy Garland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c9b", "question": "What John Steinbeck novel gets its title from a lyric in \"The Battle Hymn of the Republic\"?", "answer": "The Grapes of Wrath", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6db", "question": "What name is given to a ball on a wire that is thrown in an Olympic event?", "answer": "Hammer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ae4", "question": "What 2001 Rachael Leigh Cook film was based on an old Saturday morning cartoon series?", "answer": "Josie and the Pussycats", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ded21eea2747c8aff16d3a", "question": "Which 19th century French artist painted \"Bathers at Asnieres\"?", "answer": "Georges Seurat", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339287", "question": "In season 14 of the TV show \"Big Brother\" what coach lost all but one player in the first week but kept until final 3?", "answer": "Dan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5af25146b63e5727cf5a4838", "question": "What place does Argentina take on the list of the World\u2019s largest countries by land area?", "answer": "Eighth", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ac7", "question": "What was E.T.'s favorite candy in the movie \"E.T.: The Extra Terrestrial\"?", "answer": "Reese's Pieces", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339392", "question": "Who played the role of Donnie Brasco in the movie of the same name?", "answer": "Johnny Depp", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b3724d1c3f17ccc40c8e23", "question": "What English party was politician Arthur Hayday associated with?", "answer": "Labour Party", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6bc", "question": "Which Space Shuttle broke apart during re-entry in February, 2003?", "answer": "Columbia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601b4af249076251badbeabe", "question": "Ruby Bridges became the first Black student to do what?", "answer": "At six-years-old, Ruby Bridges was the first Black child to be integrated into an all-white school in New Orleans in 1960.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb32", "question": "What supermodel appeared dressed as George Washington on the cover of the premiere issue of \"George\" magazine?", "answer": "Cindy Crawford", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecc971ec223966ae8f8896", "question": "What alias did the infamous Keyser S\u00f6ze go by throughout most of the film \"The Usual Suspects\"?", "answer": "Roger \"Verbal\" Kint", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ae862f37f28483af1e7fdc8", "question": "What country did Hawaiian pizza come from?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6010c7200775fa611bce67d6", "question": "What was Kellogg's Frosted Flakes original name?", "answer": "When the breakfast cereal was introduced in 1952, it was called \"Kellogg's Sugar Frosted Flakes of Corn\".", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133903c", "question": "Which musical term denotes that a piece is to be played \"very sweetly\"?", "answer": "Dolcissimo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f96", "question": "Handel's \"Largo\" comes from which opera?", "answer": "Xerxes", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a83c", "question": "How many US states border Ohio?", "answer": "5", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b96a", "question": "What is the sixth commandment?", "answer": "Thou shalt not kill", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f6ea4a9e54d890926f6c8", "question": "Which Caribbean island is the closest to the United States coast?", "answer": "Bimini -- It is a tiny Bahamian island and is located just 50 miles east of Miami, Florida.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133978c", "question": "Who played Rachel Green on the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "Jennifer Aniston", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0ed", "question": "What famous speech delivered on November 19, 1863, lasted only two minutes?", "answer": "Gettysburg Address", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5941260abab1e6f9796f1b57", "question": "In Greek mythology, \"Sirens\" were represented as a combination of woman and what animal?", "answer": "Bird", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59da1bfaf6756c9b30ba14ff", "question": "Who was the star of the TV cooking show \"The Galloping Gourmet\"?", "answer": "Graham Kerr", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecc32dec223966ae8f887b", "question": "What singer staged a comeback with \"The Emancipation of Mimi,\" the second-best-selling album worldwide in 2005?", "answer": "Mariah Carey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133914b", "question": "Who was the Greek god of fire?", "answer": "Hephaestus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133931a", "question": "In the 1967 movie \"Cool Hand Luke\", how many hard-boiled eggs does Lucas eat in one hour?", "answer": "50", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e8a8962404ad935a7e1a63f", "question": "Which Premier League team's mascot is the Red Devil?", "answer": "Manchester United", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b389", "question": "Guru Nanak founded which religion?", "answer": "Sikhism", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ec22f68dc25ca9e12ef62b", "question": "As whom was J\u00e1n Ludv\u00edk Hyman Binyamin Hoch better known?", "answer": "Robert Maxwell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c79d", "question": "What is the only moon in our solar system to spin in a direction opposite of its planet's rotation?", "answer": "Triton", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac59", "question": "What year did the red maple leaf design officially become Canada's flag?", "answer": "1965", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ec7227f57c9fcac0ce71976", "question": "What is the longest running sporting event in the United States?", "answer": "The Kentucky Derby", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5be580b85415ba52ed6f0ab7", "question": "What is the capital of Qatar?", "answer": "Doha", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60078ae40eee65b76b9f2661", "question": "Following a steel shortage, what kind of ships were built during World War I?", "answer": "Concrete (24 ships were completed too late to join the war efforts, but the concept was applied to make ships used during World War II.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac27", "question": "The Panama Canal connects the Gulf of Panama and which sea?", "answer": "Caribbean sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a85b", "question": "On which harbour is the Sydney Opera House located?", "answer": "Sydney Harbour", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015e4dcfe83fe1f2a824bb8", "question": "Anubis, the God of Death, had the head of a what?", "answer": "Jackal", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a49c", "question": "What is the deepest part of the Atlantic Ocean?", "answer": "Milwaukee Deep", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e74", "question": "Who played the blind character in the movie \"City Lights\"?", "answer": "Virginia Cherrill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a603", "question": "What Australian state surrounds the city of Canberra?", "answer": "New South Wales", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d5c", "question": "What song did the Drifters follow with the 1964 sequel \"I've Got Sand in My Shoes\"?", "answer": "Under the Boardwalk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab54", "question": "What sea does Slovenia have water access to?", "answer": "Adriatic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecc143ec223966ae8f8867", "question": "In 1908, boxer Jack Johnson became the first African-American to do what?", "answer": "Win the heavyweight title", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600cc2406de0eb824d4052e5", "question": "Norman Rockwell is the official artist of which state?", "answer": "Massachusetts -- He spent 25 years living in the Berkshires of Massachusetts.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338af8", "question": "Which character killed Grendel?", "answer": "Beowulf", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c1f", "question": "Which body part was Achilles weak spot?", "answer": "His heel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59071d823745b36be73039d9", "question": "What year did the Space Race between the United States and the Soviet Union start?", "answer": "1955", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1f7", "question": "In 41 BC, who ordered the death of her sister, Arsino IV?", "answer": "Cleopatra", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339590", "question": "What movie starring Bruce Willis contains the line \"I see dead people\"?", "answer": "The Sixth Sense", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b57e", "question": "What is nori, an ingredient used in the making of sushi?", "answer": "Seaweed", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeeb", "question": "Which U.S. President ended his country's participation in the Vietnam War?", "answer": "Richard Nixon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015e19afe83fe1f2a824b97", "question": "Why did the British Royal Navy attack French warships at Mers-el-Kebir?", "answer": "The French crews refused to surrender their ships when the British requested", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff20eab31a458464a93c428", "question": "Who composed \"Ride of the Valkyries\"?", "answer": "Richard Wagner", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b03d", "question": "In 1969, what woman said \"No woman, in my time, will ever be Prime Minister\"?", "answer": "Margaret Thatcher", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1b7", "question": "Who is credited with writing three quarters of the Federalist Papers?", "answer": "Alexander Hamilton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015f031fe83fe1f2a824c10", "question": "The total number of years the Israelites spent in captivity is?", "answer": "430 -- The Israelite spent about 430 years in Egypt.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea80adff048f679a45ac1b", "question": "What type of rock dominates Yosemite National Park?", "answer": "Granite", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff0b153e662d71a53650fd0", "question": "Who founded Dumbledore's Army?", "answer": "Hermione Granger", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b913", "question": "Barbara Milicent Roberts is better known as?", "answer": "Barbie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be12", "question": "When going directly to jail, a Monopoly player is commanded not to do what two things?", "answer": "Do not pass Go, Do not collect $200.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c1b0877e98cb9777897a", "question": "What hotel was made famous by the movie \"Lost in Translation\"?", "answer": "Park Hyatt Tokyo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3a2", "question": "What is the official language of Egypt?", "answer": "Arabic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5e4", "question": "What hangs from the roof of a limestone cave?", "answer": "Stalactites", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe0e386fcbed638185eaa22", "question": "What U.S. state is nicknamed \"The Sooner State\"?", "answer": "Oklahoma", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a230", "question": "Who played the title role in the film \"Mad Max Beyond Thunderdome\"?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec8c8aec223966ae8f884c", "question": "Which famous Christmas movie is based on the story of a boy outsmarting a couple of adult thieves?", "answer": "\"Home Alone\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e3", "question": "Who is the author of the \"Bourne Trilogy\" novel series?", "answer": "Robert Ludlum", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6a4c320565ad31a57c7c2", "question": "What US President appointed the first Black Supreme Court justice?", "answer": "Lyndon B Johnson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600244004be4723ccac2219f", "question": "Snowball and Napoleon are pigs who appear in which George Orwell novel?", "answer": "\"Animal Farm\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59bb2ad5c9bff04efae6d762", "question": "How was Mark Feld better known in the 1970s?", "answer": "Marc Bolan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7ce29877e98cb97778a3d", "question": "What U.S city is nicknamed the \"Cradle of Aviation\"?", "answer": "Dayton, Ohio", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390be", "question": "What character is writer Colin Dexter most famous for creating?", "answer": "Inspector Morse", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5f9f4100af848b908361b86e", "question": "What is the opening line of Rick Astley's \"Never Gonna Give You Up\" song?", "answer": "We're no strangers to love", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339022", "question": "In Greek mythology, who was the hunter who was torn apart by Artemis' dogs?", "answer": "Actaeon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b535", "question": "How many pawns does each player have at the start of a chess game?", "answer": "Eight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4de4c06d333868d34d712", "question": "Octavian defeated Mark Anthony in which famous naval battle of 31 B.C.?", "answer": "The Battle of Actium", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b7ffbb23a3a814d89068c69", "question": "What is Freddie Mercury's birth name?", "answer": "Farrokh Bulsara", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f1684df7c52aae91cc07c5", "question": "Selaphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Light flashes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f71d5a9e54d890926f6e6", "question": "What Texas National Park is larger than the state of Rhode Island?", "answer": "Big Bend National Park -- Established in 1935, it is located along the Rio Grande River in southern Texas\u2019s Chihuahuan Desert.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf96", "question": "What is the fear of tapeworms known as?", "answer": "Taeniophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c723", "question": "Chondromalacia is the medical term for what?", "answer": "Runner's knee", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b485", "question": "What was the Republic of Nauru previously known as?", "answer": "Pleasant Island", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ad7ebc7b24f84e0b9f9ffe0", "question": "Which drummer led a band called \"The Jazz Messengers\"?", "answer": "Art Blakey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59067dbfff9c0647b50a8073", "question": "Which gaming franchise celebrated its 20th anniversary on February 27, 2016?", "answer": "Pokemon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fffa2ff73838c5c8a417f1d", "question": "What is the scientific name for Earth's crust?", "answer": "Lithosphere", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600b86961d8c1817608d53e6", "question": "What kind of person shall not be honored on a US postal stamp, according to the USPS and the Citizen\u2019s Stamp Advisory Committee?", "answer": "A living person", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe65592ae7e414034b5aeb4", "question": "What material was the first artificial Christmas tree made from?", "answer": "Goose feathers", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7d7", "question": "What extinct subspecies of zebra had stripes in front but a plain brown hindquarters?", "answer": "The quagga", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339882", "question": "In The Hobbit, how many dwarves show up at Bilbos house?", "answer": "13", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae9d", "question": "Who was the last alleged witch to be executed for witchcraft in the British Isles?", "answer": "Janet Horne", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339226", "question": "What country provided most of the settings for \"The Lord of the Rings\" movies?", "answer": "New Zealand", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5c2", "question": "Which two US states begin with the letter \"V\"?", "answer": "Vermont and Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133934b", "question": "Who was the first host of \"The Tonight Show\"?", "answer": "Steve Allen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b98", "question": "Whose paintings include \"Campbell's Soup Can\" and \"Green Coca-Cola Bottles\"?", "answer": "Andy Warhol", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aed3", "question": "Of what nationality was explorer Captain James Cook?", "answer": "British", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0e6", "question": "On what date did the Menendez murders take place?", "answer": "August 20, 1989", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c31a", "question": "Approximately how many miles are there in a nautical mile?", "answer": "1.15", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea793aff048f679a45abe0", "question": "What nerve tissue transmits light signals from your eye lens to the brain?", "answer": "Retina", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c60b", "question": "What is the fear of washing or bathing called?", "answer": "Ablutophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59bb29c1c9bff04efae6d759", "question": "Whose novels include \"The Joy Luck Club\" and \"The Kitchen God's Wife\"?", "answer": "Amy Tan's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb64", "question": "What rank in the US Army is just above the rank of First Lieutenant?", "answer": "Captain", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5900873f5304ceedb84e8995", "question": "What drink began in Morison's drug store in Waco, Texas in 1885?", "answer": "Dr. Pepper", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fef65ca6ce05a3942286e71", "question": "In \"Saved by the Bell\", the main characters create a band called what?", "answer": "Zack Attack", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339729", "question": "Which musical instrument was Buddy Rich best known for playing?", "answer": "Drums", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b22f", "question": "In 1641, who married Mary Stuart, the daughter of England's King Charles I?", "answer": "William of Orange", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c93f", "question": "What is the slowest moving, living land mammal?", "answer": "Three-toed sloth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b454", "question": "Where did Abraham Lincoln give his historic speech?", "answer": "Gettysburg, Pennsylvania", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdff6ab1cf6db9ac4808cf0", "question": "Where is the longest freshwater beach in the world?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe3eafe38e4e5d4832e6317", "question": "Which company produced the World War II fighter plane \"Spitfire\"?", "answer": "Triumph", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c00", "question": "What cartoon earned Garry Trudeau a Pulitzer Prize in 1975?", "answer": "Doonesbury", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339014", "question": "In Egyptian mythology, who is the god of the underworld?", "answer": "Osiris", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef92186ce05a3942286e80", "question": "What does Paul McCartney reportedly do in the background of the Beach Boys song \"Vegetables\"?", "answer": "Munch on a celery", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acea", "question": "Which president's wife helped fund the war effort by auctioning wool from sheep grazing on the White House lawn?", "answer": "Woodrow Wilson's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "594a63192ebb971c1417fb97", "question": "What year did the \"Turbot War\" fishing dispute end?", "answer": "1996", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ec", "question": "Which actor played the role of Edward Scissorhands?", "answer": "Johnny Depp", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4de8b06d333868d34d717", "question": "Which Roman Emperor built a massive wall across Northern Britain in 122 A.D.?", "answer": "Hadrian", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c905", "question": "What is another name for the prairie wolf?", "answer": "Coyote", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4ed9606d333868d34d76e", "question": "In what type of language does the meaning change based on your pitch?", "answer": "Tonal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bea6", "question": "What hobby uses the Yoshizawa-Randlett diagramming system?", "answer": "Origami", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399ae", "question": "The first spin-off of C.S.I., starting in 2002, was set in what city?", "answer": "Miami", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fede1366ce05a3942286dc3", "question": "In the 2006 movie \"Flicka,\" what type of animal is Flicka?", "answer": "Horse", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6cb", "question": "Which US state is home to Lassen Volcano National Park?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397cd", "question": "Who played Sofia in the movie \"The Color Purple\"?", "answer": "Oprah Winfrey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a56d", "question": "Which US capital city was originally called Le Fleur's Bluff?", "answer": "Jackson", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ea5", "question": "In what comic strip would you find siblings Honi and Hamlet?", "answer": "Hagar the Horrible", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6dd", "question": "What constellation represents a hunter with a club a shield?", "answer": "Orion", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f98", "question": "What character from a pop song wears electric boots and a mohair suit?", "answer": "Bennie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e90fe44d7247dfc0fa00308", "question": "Who was the first character Walt Disney created?", "answer": "Oswald the Lucky Rabbit", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e9c", "question": "What Steinbeck novel takes its title from a poem by Julia Ward Howe?", "answer": "The Grapes of Wrath", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339da5", "question": "Who played the role of the US president in the movie \"Being There\"?", "answer": "Jack Warden", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f6e7ff048f679a45aae0", "question": "The San Andreas Fault is an example of what type of tectonic plate boundary?", "answer": "Transform plate boundary", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2f6", "question": "What 1966 science fiction film staring Raquel Welch did Richard Fleischer direct?", "answer": "Fantastic Voyage", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338894", "question": "What did Rumpelstiltskin spin into gold?", "answer": "Straw", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b804", "question": "In a Scrabble game, what is the term for using all seven letters in one turn?", "answer": "Bingo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339306", "question": "In the movie \"Top Gun\", what is the name of Maverick's Radar Intercept Officer?", "answer": "Goose", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ed8", "question": "What pieces of fruit contain three princesses in Sergei Prokofiev's most famous opera?", "answer": "Oranges", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58c89d41011619dd6d415484", "question": "What book did Butters write as a sequel to \"Scrotie McBoogerballs\"?", "answer": "The Poop That Took a Pee", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59523c9d736d4be723796b39", "question": "What are Canada\u2019s two official sports?", "answer": "Ice hockey and lacrosse", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a9e94357ccba3ffe45786d0", "question": "What element is assigned the chemical symbol Cf?", "answer": "Californium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59067dc4ff9c0647b50a8074", "question": "Which gaming franchise celebrated its 20th anniversary on February 27, 2016?", "answer": "Pokemon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b53f", "question": "What letter is least used in the English language?", "answer": "Z", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd6b", "question": "In photography, what kind of \"number\" is used to measure lens speed?", "answer": "f", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfe6", "question": "What country saw the origin of lawn tennis?", "answer": "England", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396a2", "question": "Who played the role of Harold Payne in the 1994 movie \"Speed\"?", "answer": "Dennis Hopper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa28", "question": "A statue of Billy Bremner stands outside the ground of which football stadium?", "answer": "Leeds United", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ef9", "question": "Which literary work's title character is named Offred?", "answer": "The Handmaid's Tale", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58ab974986faa38a764be528", "question": "What country did the Lada car brand originate from?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdb4", "question": "Each Pac-Man maze features 240 regular dots and how many larger \"power pellets\"?", "answer": "Four", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd6632fa5bfecdd737e084d", "question": "Who had the highest grossing tour of 2018?", "answer": "Ed Sheeran", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133915b", "question": "Who directed the movie \"The Godfather\"?", "answer": "Francis Ford Coppola", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6002449b4be4723ccac221a6", "question": "What artist is known for having painted the Moulin Rouge?", "answer": "Henri de Toulouse-Lautrec produced a collection of provocative images of the decadent life of 19th century Paris.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe65860ae7e414034b5aeee", "question": "Who was Odette Sansom in World War II?", "answer": "Female British spy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a5", "question": "What is the name of Doc Brown's very clever dog in the \"Back to the Future\" movie franchise?", "answer": "Einstein", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b81b", "question": "What number is a thousand thousands?", "answer": "A million", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392eb", "question": "In the 1991 movie \"Thelma and Louise\" who plays the part of Thelma?", "answer": "Geena Davis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bda6", "question": "What slot on the back of an arrow's shaft keeps it on the bowstring?", "answer": "The nock", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a944", "question": "What name is given to the mainland peninsula that's part of Hong Kong?", "answer": "Kowloon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fc2f38dcee580c7f8fd1e56", "question": "Who was the skipper of PT 109 during World War II?", "answer": "John F. Kennedy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58dba40a874c93a3298b2142", "question": "Puccini's \"Tosca\" is based on which 1887 Victorien Sardou play?", "answer": "La Tosca", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339431", "question": "Who both wrote and starred in the 1996 movie \"From Dusk Till Dawn\"?", "answer": "Quentin Tarantino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab06", "question": "What was Genghis Khan's birth name?", "answer": "Temujin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338af2", "question": "Pablo Picasso was one of the suspects questioned when what item was stole in Paris in 1911?", "answer": "The Mona Lisa", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2a4", "question": "What does the equation E=mc2 represent?", "answer": "Mass-energy equivalency", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f3c", "question": "According to Erma Bombeck's best seller, where is the grass always greener?", "answer": "Over the septic tank", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5909cbb9bb53d1af658864da", "question": "Which artist recorded the Christmas song \"Run Rudolph Run\" in 1958?", "answer": "Chuck Berry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c7a", "question": "What war is the setting for the novel \"All Quiet on the Western Front\"?", "answer": "World War I", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a02", "question": "What Shakespeare play is set on January 5?", "answer": "Twelfth Night", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2e6", "question": "What US state has been led by Harold Stassen and Jesse Ventura?", "answer": "Minnesota", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af30", "question": "From what terrible disease did Robert the Bruce suffer?", "answer": "Leprosy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af15", "question": "President Abraham Lincoln was a member of which political party?", "answer": "Republican Party", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe9f0c7ff048f679a45aaa6", "question": "Technophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Technology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59029d60cad1ec93f27df74d", "question": "Where did Thomas Lipton open his first grocery store?", "answer": "Glasgow, Scotland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dc7", "question": "What double-word song title was a hit single by David Bowie?", "answer": "Rebel Rebel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "591c3838815febcc896f927c", "question": "What is the twelfth sign of the Zodiac?", "answer": "Pisces", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e805e5de59ea584496fead", "question": "Which South African town was severely damaged by the Boland Earthquake in September 1969?", "answer": "Tulbagh", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58b8cd1794b094db915830a4", "question": "How many Academy Award nominations did Leonardo DiCaprio receive before finally winning the award for Best Actor in 2016?", "answer": "6", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b87a", "question": "How many rooms are there on a standard \"Clue\" game board?", "answer": "Nine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7cf", "question": "Bucharest is the capital of what country?", "answer": "Romania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339be8", "question": "The TV show \"Seinfeld\" is a show about what?", "answer": "Nothing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd66479a5bfecdd737e0855", "question": "Who was the first US president to be heard on the radio?", "answer": "Warren Harding", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbfc", "question": "The shoe company Converse is owned by what major corporation?", "answer": "Nike", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d61", "question": "Who wrote the 1963 novel \"Planet of the Apes\"?", "answer": "Pierre Boulle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8f08401dd7bf43be5e7fd", "question": "How did pound cake get its name?", "answer": "Having one pound of each main ingredient", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a90d", "question": "What major river runs through Seoul?", "answer": "Han", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d03", "question": "What John Grisham novel features a female attorney named Regina Love, who goes by the nickname \"Reggie\"?", "answer": "The Client", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa26", "question": "What ocean separates North America from Europe?", "answer": "Atlantic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8aa6b01dd7bf43be5e75a", "question": "What\u2019s another name for a footrest?", "answer": "Ottoman", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3ca", "question": "Which poisonous concoction was Socrates given to drink to carry out his death sentence?", "answer": "Hemlock", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c07", "question": "What was Anna Nicole Smith's full birth name?", "answer": "Vickie Lynn Hogan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5901d831709c1c34536e6ea5", "question": "What is the protective coating called that covers chicken eggs when they're hatched?", "answer": "Bloom", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a409", "question": "Through which continent does the Crocodile River run?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339599", "question": "Who played the roles of Harry and Sally in the movie \"When Harry Met Sally\"?", "answer": "Billy Crystal and Meg Ryan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abef", "question": "What country borders Ukraine to the east?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a79", "question": "What city does Jackie Moon's team play for in the 2008 movie \"Semi-Pro\"?", "answer": "Flint, Michigan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d9d", "question": "Who played the role of the US president in the movie \"Dave\"?", "answer": "Kevin Kline", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51d2fff04d658268c9323", "question": "When the first Burger King Restaurant opened in 1954, how much did a hamburger cost?", "answer": "18 cents -- That is what David Edgerton charged for a hamburger when he opened the first Burger King Restaurant.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6014c868fbde8045e48466d8", "question": "The San Andreas Fault is an example of what type of tectonic plate boundary?", "answer": "The San Andreas Fault is a continental transform fault, meaning the plates slide past each other along a fault line.", "category": "science"}]